http://www.medifast1.com/privacy

Privacy Policy
I. ABOUT THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND USING OUR SITE AND TOOLS This Privacy Policy applies to websites provided by Medifast, Inc., Medifast Weight Control Centers and OPTAVIA LLC and their subsidiaries and affiliates ("Company" or "We" or "Our"). Within this privacy policy, the term "Company Websites" pertains to any and all websites hosted and/or operated by Medifast, Inc., Medifast Weight Control Centers and OPTAVIA LLC, including co-branded, product and divisional websites which link to this Privacy Policy. The Company Websites contain links to other sites.
The Company Websites contain links to other sites. Once you enter another website, be aware that Company is not responsible for the privacy
practices of such other sites. We encourage you to look for and review the privacy statements of each and every website that you visit through
links on the Company Websites. We hope that reading Our Privacy Policy gives you a clear idea of how We manage information about you. While you may use some of the functionality of the Company Websites without registering for an account, many of the specific tools
and services on the Company Websites require registration. If you choose to register with the Company Websites for certain services,
We require you to submit Personal Data. Depending on the tool or service you have selected, the Personal Data we collect may include
Personal Health Information such as your weight, health conditions, and medications, among other information. "Personal Data" means any
information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person ('data subject') (or under certain laws, an identified or
identifiable household or legal entity where such information is protected similarly); an identifiable natural person is one who
can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, email address, mailing address
or phone number or an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical,
physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person. You are responsible for ensuring the accuracy of the Personal Data you submit to the Company Websites. Inaccurate information
will affect the information you receive when using the Company Websites and tools and Our ability to contact you as contemplated
in this Privacy Policy. For example, your email address should be kept current because that is how We communicate with you. II. INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU Even if you do not register with the Company Websites, We collect information about your use of the Company Websites, special
promotions and newsletters. We collect the following specific categories of Personal Data:
Identifiers, such as your name, postal address, email address, account name, or other similar identifiers; Protected characteristics, such as your gender, age, race, or other protected classifications under applicable law; Commercial information, such as products or services purchased, or other purchasing or consumption histories or tendencies; Internet or other electronic network activity information, such as browsing history, search history, or information regarding your interaction with the Company Websites; Financial, medical, or health insurance information, such as weight, health conditions, and medications; Inferences regarding preferences or other characteristics; and Education Information such as undergraduate and graduate degrees and professional licenses.
We collect this information from the following categories of sources:
From your device or browser; Directly from you when you provide information; and From your Habits of Health application.
Below we describe how we collect this information. Automatically Collected Information A. Cookies We collect information about your use of the Company Websites and your use of the websites of selected sponsors and advertisers
through the use of Cookies. The Company Websites and Our sponsors' or advertisers' websites assign every computer a different
Cookie. The information collected by Cookies (i) helps us dynamically generate advertising and content on web pages or in
newsletters, and (ii) allows us to statistically monitor how many people are using the Company Websites and selected
sponsors' and advertisers' sites, how many people open Our emails, and for what purposes these actions are being taken.
We may use Cookie information to target certain advertisements to your browser or to determine the popularity of certain
content or advertisements. Cookies are also used to facilitate a user's log-in, as navigation aids, and as session timers,
but not to retain Personal Health Information about you. Your browser software can be set to reject all Cookies. Most browsers offer instructions on how to reset the browser to
reject Cookies in the "Help" section of the toolbar. If you reject Our Cookies, certain of the functions and conveniences
of the Company Websites may not work properly but you do not have to accept Our Cookies in order to productively use the Company Websites. We and Our service providers also use Cookies to collect information from you over time and across the
Company Websites and other websites to provide you with and improve the performance of Our advertising that Our service providers
deliver to you on other websites. You may opt-out of receiving future commercial emails by clicking on the "unsubscribe"
link at the end of commercial e-mails or following instructions on how to unsubscribe from the mailing list. Some of Our service providers may offer the ability to opt out of their use of your information for the placement of
targeted advertisements. To opt out of these service providers' use of your information for the placement of targeted advertisements,
please visit http://optout.aboutads.info. We do not currently respond to web browser "do not track" signals or other mechanisms
that provide a method to opt out of the collection of information across the networks of websites and online services in which We participate.
For more information about "do not track" signals, visit http://www.allaboutdnt.org B. Web Beacons We also use Web Beacons to collect information about your use of the Company Websites and the websites of selected sponsors and
advertisers, and your use of special promotions or newsletters. The information collected by Web Beacons allows us to
statistically monitor your usage of the Company Websites. We do not link information from Web Beacons to your personal details without your permission and do not use Web
Beacons to collect or store Personal Health Information about you. C. Third-Party Web Beacons We use third-party web beacons to help analyze where visitors go and what they do while visiting the Company Websites. We
allow search engines to use web beacons on the Company Websites to collect information about your visits to this and other
websites in order to improve its products and services and provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. Information You Provide We collect Personal Data that you provide to us when you register as a member of the Company Websites and/or when you update your member profile. We may be required by law to collect certain Personal Data about you or as a consequence of any contractual relationship we have with you.
Failure to provide this information may prevent or delay the fulfillment of these obligations. D. Emails You Send to the Company Websites This Privacy Policy does not protect you when you send content, business information, ideas, concepts or inventions to the Company Websites by email.
If you want to keep content or business information, ideas, concepts or inventions private or proprietary, do not send them in an email to any of
the Company Websites. E. Website Registration and Interactive Tools on the Company Websites After you have registered as a member of the Company Websites, you may choose to use certain interactive content, tools and services that may ask you to
voluntarily provide other types of information about yourself including Personal Health Information. F. Children The Company Websites do not sell products for purchase by children. We sell products for purchase by adults. If you are under 18, you may only use
the Company Websites with the involvement of a parent or guardian. In this case, a parent or guardian is solely responsible for providing supervision
of the minor's use of the Company Websites. The parent or guardian assumes full responsibility for ensuring that the registration information is
kept secure and that the information submitted is accurate. The parent or guardian also assumes full responsibility for the interpretation and use
of any information or suggestions provided through the Company Websites for the minor. If you become aware that your child has provided their
Personal Data through the Company Websites, please contact us at the contact information provided below. G. Market Research From time to time the Company marketing department, or operations contractors acting on its behalf, may conduct online research surveys in order
to gather feedback about the Company Websites through email invitations, pop-up surveys or online focus groups. When participating in a survey,
We may ask you to submit Personal Data. This Personal Data is used for research purposes, and is not used for sales solicitations. When an
external party sponsors a survey, information from the survey results is reported to the sponsor. Personal Data collected through market research
will only be used by Company and its operations contractors and will not be given or sold to an external party without your consent. III. USE OF YOUR INFORMATION We use the Personal Data that you provide to:
respond to your questions, as it is in Our legitimate interest to provide you appropriate responses; verify your identity when you access and use our services, and ensure the security of your Personal Data, so We can comply with Our contractual obligations to you; provide you the specific services you select, so We can comply with Our contractual obligations to you; analyze how you use our services and improve our services, as it is in Our legitimate interest to understand any issues with our services and improve them; send you emails about website maintenance and updates, and inform you of significant changes to this Privacy Policy, as it is in Our legitimate interest to provide you with notices about Our services; communicate with you about offers, products, and services that may be of interest to you, as it is in Our legitimate interest to make the messages we send more
relevant and interesting-where required by law, we will obtain your consent first; exercise our rights where it is necessary to do so, for example to detect, prevent, and respond to fraud, intellectual property infringement, or violations of law or contract; and comply with our legal and regulatory obligations.
IV. DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy or as specifically agreed to by you, the Company will not disclose any Personal Data it gathers from you through the
Company Websites. We may disclose the following categories of your Personal Data for business purposes:
Identifiers; Protected characteristics; Commercial information; Internet or other electronic network activity information; Financial, medical, or health information; Inferences drawn from any of the above information categories; and Educational information.
We disclose these categories of Personal Data for business purposes as described below: We disclose Personal Data: (1) to comply with valid legal requirements such as a law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena or court order; or
(2) in special cases, such as a physical threat to you or others. In the event that We are legally compelled to disclose your Personal Data to an
external party, We will attempt to notify you unless doing so would violate the law or court order. If you are a Client of OPTAVIA, in order to provide you with the products and services you have requested, We may share your Personal Data, including,
but not limited to, your name, contact information (such as e-mail, address and phone number), as well as product order history, with your personal
Independent OPTAVIA Coach and other Independent OPTAVIA Coaches in your personal Independent OPTAVIA Coach’s up line organization. However, any payment
information you may give to the Company in the course of ordering Our products will only be disclosed to the Company’s Client Success Team or Coach
Success Team members and will not be available to any external parties for any reason except to comply with valid legal requirements. Coaches who
receive your information have agreed not to share your information with any external parties and are obligated to observe the intent of this Privacy
Policy under the terms of their Independent OPTAVIA Coach Agreement with the Company. If you are an OPTAVIA Coach, you will receive mentorship, advice and information from your own sponsoring Business Coach and your Business Coach's up line organization.
To allow such mentorship and communication, We may share your Personal Data as well as other data related to your business with your Business Coach and Coaches in
your Business Coach's up line organization. In the ordinary course of supporting your business, information about you, as well as product order history may also be
shared with your sponsoring Business Coach and your Business Coach's up line organization. Coaches who receive your information have agreed not to share your
information with any third parties and are obligated to observe the intent of this Privacy Policy under the terms of their Independent OPTAVIA Coach Agreement
with the Company. We also share your information in limited form with third party operations and maintenance contractors who need to use that information in the course of
their provision of products or services to the Company. These contractors include vendors and suppliers that provide us with technology, services, and/or
content related to better operation and maintenance of the Company Websites. Access to your Personal Data by these contractors is limited to the information
reasonably necessary for the contractor to perform its limited function for the Company Websites. We also contractually require that Our operations and
maintenance contractors:
protect the privacy of your Personal Data consistent with this Privacy Policy; and not use or disclose your Personal Data for any purpose other than providing us with products and services.
We periodically share this information, including your personal improvement and weight-loss related information, with Company partners. This includes
companies that are controlled by, or are under common control with Medifast Inc., Independent Medifast Weight Control Centers, Medifast independent
distributors and "OPTAVIA Coaches". These partners use your information to make predictions about your interests and reach out to you with special
offers, promotions, advertisements, newsletters, and other materials. Where required by law, we will obtain your consent prior to such sharing. V. HOW COMPANY HANDLES PRIVACY AND SECURITY INTERNALLY Listed below are some of the security procedures that Company uses to protect your privacy:
Requires both an email address and a password in order for users to access their Personal Data, including Personal Health Information. Uses encryption technology to protect your Personal Data, including credit card information, as it is transmitted to us. Uses firewalls and other intrusion detection and prevention technologies to protect information stored on our servers. Closely monitors the limited number of Company employees who have potential access to your Personal Data. Requires all Company employees to abide by Our Privacy Policy and be subject to disciplinary action if they violate it. Systems back-ups to protect the integrity of your Personal Data. Provides secure messaging within the Company Websites so that information related to your personal health is sent through a secure, encrypted connection.
Despite Company efforts to protect your Personal Data, including Personal Health Information, there is always some risk that an unauthorized
third party may find a way around Our security systems or that transmissions of your information over the Internet will be intercepted. VI. UPDATING YOUR INFORMATION AND CONTACTING COMPANY
A. Updating Your Personal Data The Company Websites' pages that collect and store self-reported data allow you to correct, update or review information you have submitted by going
back to the specific page, logging-in and making the desired changes. B. Removing your Personal Data If you have a complaint or problem, including a request to access or to remove your personal data from Our systems,
please open this link and fill in this form which will allow Us to
validate your identity and fulfil your request or call us at 1-888-678-2842 (OPTAVIA). Our customer service
department will forward your request to the appropriate internal Company department for a response or resolution. You may also write us at: Attn: Privacy Officer 100 International Drive 18th Floor Baltimore, MD 21202 C. Limitations on Removing or Changing Information Upon your request, We will delete your Personal Data from Our active databases and where feasible from Our back-up media. You
should be aware that it may not be possible to remove each and every record of the information you have provided to the
Company Websites from Our servers. In addition, you may have certain rights regarding your Personal Data, subject to local law. These include the following rights to:
access your information; rectify the information we hold about you; erase your information; restrict Our use of your information; object to Our use of your information; receive your information in a usable electronic format and transmit it to a third party (right to data portability); learn more about the sources from which we collect information, the purposes for which we collect and share information, the information we hold, and the categories of parties with whom we share your information; exercise rights without fear of being denied goods or services; lodge a complaint with your local data protection authority; and where the processing of your information is based on your consent, you have the right to withdraw consent at any time, without
affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal.
Please note that we will likely require additional information from you in order to honor your requests. If you would like to discuss or exercise such rights, please contact us at the details provided above. VII. DATA RETENTION POLICY We will keep your Personal Data for as long as we have a relationship with you for the purposes of providing Our services.
When deciding how long to keep your information after Our relationship with you has ended, we take into account Our legal
obligations and regulators' expectations. We may also retain records to investigate or defend potential legal claims. VIII. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY Company retains the right to update this Privacy Policy at its general discretion according to the needs of
the business, its consumers or in accordance with the mandates of federal and state law. If We update this
Privacy Policy, We will notify you by posting a new Privacy Policy on this page or by notifying you through the
Company Websites or at other contact information We have on file for you. If any such update materially increases
the ways in which We collect, use or share the information previously collected from you through the Company Websites,
We will give you the opportunity to consent to such changes before applying them to that information. This version of the privacy policy is effective January 1, 2020.
Legal Notices
Terms & Conditions of Use
Trademarks
Privacy Policy
Digital Millennium Copyright Act
Unsolicited Product Submission Policy
Lose big, save big and earn rewards. 100% satisfaction guaranteed!Learn More
